# A. Bradley Duthie

I am an evolutionary ecologist and ecological modeller with broad interests in developing theory across the biological and environmental sciences. My research primarily uses mathematical and individual-based models to understand complex interactions in populations, communities, and social-ecological systems. I am especially interested in applying these modelling approaches to questions concerning the evolution and maintenance of biodiversity, and the management of populations under conservation conflict.

### **Professional Appointments**

**Leverhulme Trust Early Career Fellow**, Nov. 2017 – Oct. 2020 Biological and Environmental Sciences, University of Stirling

**ERC Postdoctoral Research Assistant**, Nov. 2016 – Oct. 2017 Biological and Environmental Sciences, University of Stirling

**ERC Postdoctoral Research Fellow**, Jun. 2013 – Oct. 2016 School of Biological Sciences, University of Aberdeen

#### Education

**Ph.D. Ecology and Evolutionary Biology**, Spring 2013 Graduate Minor: Statistics Certificate: Graduate Student Teaching Certificate Iowa State University

**B.S. Biology** (Magna cum laude), Spring 2007 Specialisation: Ecology, Evolution, Environment Southern Illinois University Edwardsville

**B.S. Philosophy** (Magna cum laude), Spring 2007 Minor: Chemistry Southern Illinois University Edwardsville

#### **Publications**

- 21. Duthie, AB. PLoS Comput. Biol. In review.
- 20. Duthie, AB, et al. Method. Ecol. Evol. In press.
- 19. Cusack, JJ, et al. Conserv. Lett. In press.
- 18. Paine, CET., et al. 2018. Funct. Ecol. 32 (7):1681-1692.
- 17. Redpath, SM, et al. 2018. Trends Ecol. Evol. 33 (6):415-426.
- 16. Duthie, AB, et al. 2018. J. Evol. Biol. 31:31-45.
- 15. Duthie, AB, et al. 2016. Proc. R. Soc. B. 282:20161845.
- 14. Duthie, AB, et al. 2016. Am. Nat. 188 (6):651-667.
- 13. Duthie, AB, et al. 2016. Oikos. 125 (11):1597-1606.
- 12. Duthie, AB, et al. 2016. *Evolution*. 70 (9):1927-1943.
- 11. Frater, PN & AB Duthie. 2016. Ideas Ecol. Evol.. 9:15-18.
- 10. Reid, JM, et al. 2016. Evolution. 70 (7):1512-1529.
- 9. Reid, JM, et al. 2015. Evolution. 69 (11):2846-2861.
- 8. Duthie, AB, et al. 2015. Am. Nat. 186 (1):151-158.

## A. Bradley Duthie Ph.D., FHEA

Evolutionary Ecologist Ecological Modeller Biostatistician

3B156 University of Stirling Stirling FK9 4LA United Kingdom

- **T** (+44) 01786 467787
- (+44) 07561 408101
- alexander.duthie@stir.ac.uk brad.duthie@gmail.com
- http://bradduthie.github.io
- bradduthie

A. Bradley Duthie 2

- 7. Reid, JM, et al. 2015. J. Anim. Ecol. 84 (4):1029-1040.
- 6. Duthie, AB & JM Reid. 2015. PLoS One. 10 (4):e0125140.
- 5. Duthie, AC & AB Duthie. 2015. Polymath. 5 (1):1-22.
- 4. Reid, JM, et al. 2015. Evolution. 69 (1):59-74.
- 3. Duthie, AB, et al. 2014. Am. Nat. 183 (6):826-841.
- 2. Duthie, AB & MR Falcy. 2013. Ecol. Modell.. 251:260-270.
- 1. Duthie, AB. 2004. J. Memetics. 8 (1).

### Grants and Fellowships

Scottish Natural Heritage Tender (Co-PI; 2018)

Leverhulme Trust Early Career Fellowship (2017)

88,650 GBP

NSF Postdoctoral Research Fellowship in Biology (2013; award declined)

138,000 USD

NSF Doctoral Dissertation Improvement Grant (2010)

13,411 USD

Biotechnology Graduate Fellowship (ISU; 2007)

20,000 USD

### Leadership

**Manuscript reviewer**: Acta Oecologica, American Naturalist, Arthropod-Plant Interactions, Behavioral Ecology and Sociobiology, Biology Letters (5), BMC Evolutionary Biology, Ecology and Evolution, Evolution (3), the Journal of Animal Ecology, the Journal of Applied Ecology (2), the Journal of Theoretical Biology (3), Landscape Ecology, Molecular Ecology (2), Oikos, PLoS One, Proceedings of the Royal Society B, Royal Society Open Science, and Symbiosis

Grant reviewer: National Science Foundation (USA)

Conference organiser: Midwest Ecology and Evolution Conference at Iowa State University (2010)

Workshop organiser: European Congress of Conservation Biology in Jyväskylä, Finland (2018)

**Representative**: Post-doctoral researchers (organiser at UoS; 2017-2018), Graduate and Professional Student Senate (Senator at ISU; 2011-2013), and Graduate Research in Evolutionary Biology and Ecology (Vice President at ISU; 2009-2010)

### Computer Skills

Experience in statistical analysis, mathematical & individual-based modelling, genetic algorithms, and computer programming in C, R, and MATLAB

Use of Linux, git, and high performance computing clusters

Knowledge of HTML, Markdown, LATEX, and MS Office Suite

Course design and instruction in Blackboard

### Software Developed

All listed software is publicly available on the Comprehensive R Archive Network (CRAN) and on GitHub.

- GMSE vo.3.1.9. 2017. Generalised Management Strategy Evaluation Simulator. Written in R and C. R package link: < http://CRAN.R-project.org/package=GMSE > Website link: < https://confoobio.github.io/gmse/ >
- 1. **gamesGA** *v*1.1.3.2. 2017. Genetic Algorithm for Sequential Symmetric Games. *Written in R and C.* R package link: < http://CRAN.R-project.org/package=gamesGA >

A. Bradley Duthie

## Selected Awards

Iowa State University Teaching Excellence Award (top 10% of TAs; 2010)

Donal G. Myer Outstanding Student Award (SIUE; awarded to one science student; 2007)

Ober Honours Award in Philosophy (SIUE; awarded to one philosophy student; 2007)

Phi Kappa Phi (Collegiate Honour Society; 2006)

Chancellor's Scholarship (SIUE; full tuition for undergraduate education; 2003-2007)